Photographs of Sarah Bernhardt, 1880-1917 (MS Thr 446): Guide.
Photographs of Sarah Bernhardt,
1880-1917.
Harvard Theatre Collection, Houghton Library, Harvard University
MS Thr 446
3 boxes (1.5 linear feet)
Photographs of the French actress and sculptor Sarah Bernhardt by various photographers.
2003MT-148. Gift of Frederick R. Koch, 825 Fifth Avenue, New York, New York 10021; received: 1983 January 25.
Formerly in the possession of Suzanne Seylor. Purchased by Frederick R. Koch from Antonio Raimo, 1983 January 25.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Bernhardt (1844-1923) was a French actress and sculptor.
Arranged chronologically.
Photographs of Bernhardt, including some portraits as theatrical characters, as well as group photographs taken by the photographers Napoleon Sarony, Sydney Falk, Julius Rochlitz, among others.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In La Dame aux Camelias. Photograph by Napoleon Sarony, New York, 1880., (1); 10.7 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Cleopatra. Photograph by Napoleon Sarony, New York, 1891., (2); 9.5 x 15.2 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Portrait, 3/4 profile. Photograph by Napoleon Sarony, New York, 1892., (3); 9.5 x 14.2 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In La Dame de Chalon. Photograph by Napoleon Sarony, New York, 1892., (4); 9.5 x 14.2 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Pauline Blanchard. Photograph by Sydney Falk, 1891., (5); 10.2 x 13.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With other actress in Pauline Blanchard. Photograph by Sydney Falk, 1891., (6); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Cleopatra. Photograph by Sydney Falk, 1891., (7); 10.2 x 13.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As the Duc de Reichstadt in Rostand's L'Aiglon. Photograph by Paul Boyer, Paris, [n.d.]., (8); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In Fedora. Photograph by W. & D. Downey, London, [n.d.]., (9); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In Racine's Phedre. Photograph by W. & D. Downey, London, [n.d.]., (10); 9.2 x 13.9 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Seated, with dog. Photographer unknown., (11); 8.2 x 10.7 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Standing, with seated woman (possibly Suzanne Seylor) and an elderly man. Photographer unknown., (12); 8.2 x 10.7 cm.
- Sarah Bernhardt's summer house at Belle Ile en Mer, Brittany. Photographer unknown., (13); 12.1 x 16.5 cm.
- Sarah Bernhardt's summer house at Belle Ile en Mer, Brittany. Photographer unknown., (14); 12.1 x 16.5 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With other passengers aboard ocean liner. Photographer unknown., (15); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With group aboard liner. Photographer unknown., (16); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923 and others on R.R. pier. Photographer unknown., (17); 10.2 x 14.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Portrait, inscribed to Suzanne Seylor. Photograph by Rochlitz, Paris, 1903., (18); 20.3 x 25.4 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In La Dame aux Camelias. Photograph by Rochlitz, Paris, [n.d.]., (19); 22.8 x 27.9 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In La Dame aux Camelias. Photograph by Rochlitz, Paris, [n.d.]., (20); 22.8 x 27.9 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With group in front of theatre tent in Dallas, Texas, 1906. Photograph by Clogenson, Dallas, [1906]., (21); 17.7 x 23.5 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In front of theatre tent in Dallas, Texas. Photograph by Clogenson, Dallas, 1906., (22); 19.1 x 23.5 cm.
- Audience at Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Performance in Convention Hall, Kansas City, 28 February 1906. Photograph by A.T. Russell, Kansas City, [1906]., (23); 20.3 x 25.4 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With others in open car sightseeing. Photograph by Paul Goerke, Maintou, Colorado, [n.d.]., (24); 11.4 x 19.1 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Standing in garden. Photograph by L. Dourdin, Bourdeaux, [n.d.]., (25); 11.1 x 16.2 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In her private Pullman car. Photograph by Moffett, Chicago, 1917., (26); 15.2 x 22.8 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In Jeanne d'Oré. Societé Generale des Cinematographes "Eclipse.", (27); 15.9 x 22.8 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Jeanne d'Arc. Photograph by Reutlinger, Paris, [n.d.]., (28); 12.7 x 19.4 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With Mrs. Patrick Campbell in Pelleas et Melisande[1905]. Photograph by W. & D. Downey, London, [n.d.]., (29); 17.7 x 28.6 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. At special ceremony in Paris. Photograph by Harlingue, Paris, [n.d.]., (30); 11.7 x 17.1 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With group in snowy landscape. Photographer unknown., (31); 12.7 x 17.7 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. With group in snowy landscape. Photographer unknown. [Duplicate of (31).], (32); 12.7 x 17.7 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. At piano, with another woman standing. Photograph by Joseph Byron, New York, [n.d.]., (33); 19.4 x 24.4 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. In dressing room. Photograph by L. N. A., London, [n.d.]., (34); 19.7 x 24.1 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. On stage with others in performance. Photograph by A. Bert, Paris, [n.d.]., (35); 22.2 x 27.9 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Portrait, signed by her. Photograph by Histed, London, 1909., (36); 20.3 x 27.3 cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Hamlet. Photograph by Lafayette, London, [n.d.]., (37); 27.9 x 35.5. cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. As Hamlet, with Yorick's skull. Photograph by Lafayette, London, [n.d.]., (38); 27.9 x 35.5. cm.
- Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923. Seated, reading, as Hamlet. Photograph by Lafayette, London, [n.d.]., (39); 27.9 x 35.5 cm.
- View of "Le Fort de Sarah Bernhardt, 'Belle Ile en Mer.'" Photographer unknown., (40); 20.3 x 25.4 cm.